<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Vhvemzahp</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vhvemzahp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 11:29:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vhvemzahp.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/49436567-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 11:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/49436567-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>In recent years, there's been a growing trend of people moving away from religious belief. In the West, particularly, the demographic statistics suggest that a large number of millennials are leaving their religious upbringings behind.
There are many factors at play, but I'll focus specifically on four key issues that lead to this "religious disaffection," along with proposals for what the Church can do about it.
The four key issues can be described as follows:</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/66685978-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:48:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/66685978-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>Within the body of Christ, we are called to consider other believers as members of our family, siblings in the Lord. This call to treat one another accordingly can be an intentional effort to take on, aided by the grace of God and a biblical understanding of what it means to act "like family."
Let's unpack these principles in more detail, so we can put them into practice in our churches and personal lives.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/27686426-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 19:10:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/27686426-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>The role of the church in a democratic society is often debated. Some see the church as solely a spiritual place, advocating for moral or biblical principles in the public sphere. Others argue the church should remain separate from politics, and limited to preaching and religious worship. However, Christian influence on public freedoms and liberties is also significant, albeit not as obvious. Therefore, the church should take responsibility for its part in shaping and preserving liberties and freedoms that underpin a well-functioning democracy.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/38564919-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 13:49:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/38564919-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>It's not uncommon to hear Christian preaching and discussions that emphasize the severity of hell. Many may wonder why the focus is there instead of avoiding the notion of hell altogether or, alternatively, placing more weight on God's love and the blessings of a place like Heaven. This question particularly arises from non-believers seeking to dismiss an apparent "lack of love" in Christianity.
This article explores why hell, and by extension, its avoidance, is a relevant teaching for believers.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/94497913-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 21:51:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/94497913-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>We hear the phrase “God is love” (1 John 4:8) and, as Christians, we should strive to embody His compassion, but sometimes we fall short of that standard. In this article, we will look at what can cause us, as followers of Jesus, to be bad at being kind, so we can understand how to improve.
Self-Righteousness One of the main pitfalls for Christians that hinders us from displaying kindness is our tendency toward self-righteousness.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/71131238-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 03:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/71131238-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>I want to explore a primary reason why church consultations don’t always produce the outcomes desired. I have had the privilege of working with many churches across the nation in helping them clarify their purpose and focus on reaching people for Jesus Christ. This has allowed me to witness a variety of approaches, successes and failures. Through this experience, one significant key to the success or failure of these strategic meetings has become clear: What makes church consultations thrive or falter is the extent to which all the key leaders of the church become unified and cohesively committed to the process.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/95226949-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:22:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/95226949-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>We all want to know what the future holds, and there are various "prediction" industries that cater to our curiosity. Since time immemorial, people have speculated about the end of the world and have eagerly devoured any new theories that crop up. It is also common for people to look to religious teachings for answers. When it comes to Christianity, what does Jesus teach us about God's "end-times" plan?
This question is complex.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/31787133-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 01:52:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/31787133-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>As technology advances at a rapid pace, it seems that many of life's facets are being fundamentally altered. This has lead some to question how Christians should approach the progress in technology. For a Christian, it is important to remember our central purpose and hope: Christ and the Gospel. Therefore, the question of how we should handle technological development should be a question of how this progress serves us in fulfilling our mission while not leading us into sinful behavior.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/88825325-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 07:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/88825325-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>There is no doubt that many people have formed strong and sometimes extreme opinions about Christian fundamentalism. This is often due to the popular press labeling fundamentalists as a homogeneous group focused on fire and brimstone. However, as with any large organization, there can be found a myriad of opinions within this group. Some may focus on literal interpretations of scripture while others may have a more nuanced understanding of their faith.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/24175971-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 06:01:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/24175971-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>"Self-care is sometimes mistaken for a selfish habit. In reality, it is a holy endeavor."
Just as the incarnation of Jesus Christ revealed God's great love for humanity, it is within the realm of human self-care that we also see the hand and heart of our Creator. But what does this truly mean and how can we strive to integrate care for self more fully into our everyday lives?
The Great Divide For some, self-care may sound like indulgence, apathy or the antithesis of kindness and concern for the world outside of themselves.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/44396212-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 20:35:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/44396212-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>Everyone must have come across this phrase a few times in the Bible, because its occurrence is quite frequent. It is mentioned in the Old Testament as well as in the New Testament (James 1:27, Psalm 68:5, Isaiah 1:17 &amp;amp;1:23, Jeremiah 49:11, Zechariah 7:9–10, Leviticus 23:22 to name just a few). The use of these terms creates an impression that taking care of orphans and widows is part of certain religious or moral obligations.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/95316570-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 11:08:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/95316570-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>Pastors have a unique position in the church. They are expected to have all the answers, provide comfort, and lead their congregation, while still going through their personal struggles just like any other human being. However, pastors often find it difficult to ask for help, even though doing so would be beneficial to their spiritual well-being and the growth of their ministry. Let’s discuss the reasons behind this struggle and ways to overcome it.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/88457387-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 17:51:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/88457387-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>Two powerful forces in our lives are guilt and deception. Both can play a significant role in the Christian life. It is not uncommon for many who come to Christ to find their journey filled with moments of great struggle with both of these foes. Inevitably, these two forces will be encountered as we grow in our walk with Christ. However, the process of discipleship and growth into spiritual maturity can often illuminate our path in the way these adversaries oftentimes function.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/32086648-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 14:10:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/32086648-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>Since the beginning of time, human beings have wondered about the afterlife. With the rapid spread of Christianity over the centuries, what Christians believe about the afterlife has become a central issue for many. As various ideas about heaven have been formulated, many of them fall outside of what the Bible actually teaches. This article will explore possible reasons for the development of non-biblical ideas about heaven.
Cognitive Biases Overconfidence The overconfidence bias may contribute to inaccurate notions of heaven.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/59379427-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/59379427-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>As I’m sure you know, life is full of ups and downs. It is riddled with times of triumph as well as utter heartbreak. I have walked through a valley as dark as death. In this experience, one of the most important things that I learned was how to build confidence in God. In this article, I am going to share with you four keys to this process during some of the most difficult circumstances you may face.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/59734774-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 19:12:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/59734774-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>In the evangelical world there are loads of books, resources, and web pages dedicated to new or curious seekers with topics such as "What to Expect when You Start Following Jesus," or "The ABCs Of Becoming A Christian," etc. Many are great.
However, there are fewer materials geared toward seasoned, but sometimes stumbling, followers of Christ. In my own life journey, I've found a strange thing; I never run out of questions.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/59285195-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:17:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhvemzahp.github.io/posts/59285195-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>We must ensure that our lives are built on the solid foundation of a genuine relationship with Jesus Christ and not on shifting or faulty ground. It's an important question to contemplate.
Thinking deeply about the foundations of our lives is a powerful means of maintaining a clear focus on what truly matters in our walk with God. It enables us to re-evaluate and re-adjust our priorities, recognizing whether we're living in line with the teachings of the Bible.</description></item></channel></rss>